Guide to the Ship Scalers, Dry Dock, and Boat Yard Workers Union, Local 541 (Seattle, Washington) Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- Ship Scalers, Dry Dock, and Boat Yard Workers Union, Local 541 (Seattle, Washington) Records, 1939-1991; 4571-001; 16 cubic feet 16 boxes
  - Series VII: Member Files, 1944-1986 (Box-folder 12/1-12/44; 16/9; 12/45-14/246)
    - Subseries B: Member Files: A-Z, 1944-1986 (Box-folder 12/45-14/220)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1981 (Box-folder 14/198)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 14/199)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1982 (Box-folder 14/200)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 14/201)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 14/202)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 14/203)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1981 (Box-folder 14/204)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 14/205)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 14/206)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1982-1982 (Box-folder 14/207)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 14/208)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1984 (Box-folder 14/209)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1982 (Box-folder 14/210)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1980 (Box-folder 14/211)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 14/212)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1981 (Box-folder 14/213)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1985 (Box-folder 14/214)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1983 (Box-folder 14/215)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 14/216)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1981 (Box-folder 14/217)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1982 (Box-folder 14/218)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with W, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 14/219)
      - Member Files: Last Names Beginning with Z, 1981 (Box-folder 14/220)
    - Subseries C: Files on Employees of Local 541, 1977-1984 (Box-folder 14/221-14/246)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 14/221)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1981 (Box-folder 14/222)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1981 (Box-folder 14/223)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1977-1984 (Box-folder 14/224)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1982 (Box-folder 14/225)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1980 (Box-folder 14/226)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1981 (Box-folder 14/227)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1980 (Box-folder 14/228)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1980 (Box-folder 14/229)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1980 (Box-folder 14/230)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 14/231)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1981 (Box-folder 14/232)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1981 (Box-folder 14/233)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 14/234)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1982 (Box-folder 14/235)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1982 (Box-folder 14/236)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1983 (Box-folder 14/237)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1983 (Box-folder 14/238)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 14/239)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1983 (Box-folder 14/240)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 14/241)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1983 (Box-folder 14/242)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1983 (Box-folder 14/243)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1983 (Box-folder 14/244)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1983 (Box-folder 14/245)
      - Employee Earnings Documents, 1983 (Box-folder 14/246)
  - Series VIII: Employer Files, 1967-1986 (Box-folder 15/1-15/34)
    - Subseries A: Todd Pacific Shipyards Corporation, 1968-1986 (Box-folder 15/1-15/14)
      - Todd Pacific Shipyards Corporation: Discrimination Issues, 1968-1983 (Box-folder 15/1)
      - Correspondence: Todd Pacific Shipyards Corporation: Grievances, Affirmative Action, Contract and Policy Negotiations, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 15/2)
      - Todd Shipyards Corporation, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 15/3)
      - Fraser Boiler Service, Inc.; Todd Shipyards, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 15/4)
      - Leaflet: Todd Shipyard: New Absenteeism Policy, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 15/5)
      - Shop Steward Notes and Correspondence: Todd Pacific Shipyards Corporation, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 15/6)
      - Arbitration: Machinists Local 79 v. Todd Pacific Shipyards: New Absenteeism-Tardiness Program, 1980 (Box-folder 15/7)
      - Letter to Todd Pacific Shipyards Corporation Management from Union Business Manager Oscar Hearde: Luston House Campaigning for Union Office on Company Property, 1982 (Box-folder 15/8)
      - Data Center: Corporate Profile of Todd Shipyards Corporation: Volume I, 1982 (Box-folder 15/9)
      - Data Center: Corporate Profile of Todd Shipyards Corporation: Volume II, 1982 (Box-folder 15/10)
      - Todd Pacific Shipyards Corporation: Respirator and Facial Hair Policy, 1982 (Box-folder 15/11)
      - Todd Pacific Shipyards Corporation: Holding Sandblasters out of Seniority, 1983 (Box-folder 15/12)
      - Correspondence: Sexual Harassment at Todd Pacific Shipyards Corporation, 1984 (Box-folder 15/13)
      - Settlement Agreement: Todd Pacific Shipyard Corporation: Subcontracting Labor, 1985 (Box-folder 15/14)
    - Subseries B: Foss Launch and Tug, 1971-1986 (Box-folder 15/15-15/16)
      - Foss Launch and Tug, 1971-1980 (Box-folder 15/15)
      - Local 252: Grievances: Foss Launch and Tug: Shop Steward Robert F. Coan: Misassignment of Work, 1986 (Box-folder 15/16)
    - Subseries C: Northwest Enviroservice, Inc., 1985-1985 (Box-folder 15/17)
      - Settlement Agreement and Reinstatements: Grievance: Northwest Enviroservice, Inc.: Colleen Christiensen and Dennis Parmelee Terminations, 1985 (Box-folder 15/17)
    - Subseries D: Northwest Tank Service, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 15/18-15/23)
      - Northwest Tank Service, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 15/18)
      - Arbitration: Local 541 v. Northwest Tank Service: Discharge of Charles Campbell (1 of 4), 1980-1981 (Box-folder 15/19)
      - Arbitration: Local 541 v. Northwest Tank Service: Discharge of Charles Campbell (2 of 4), 1980-1981 (Box-folder 15/20)
      - Arbitration: Local 541 v. Northwest Tank Service: Discharge of Charles Campbell (3 of 4), 1980-1981 (Box-folder 15/21)
      - Arbitration: Local 541 v. Northwest Tank Service: Discharge of Charles Campbell (4 of 4), 1980-1981 (Box-folder 15/22)
      - Notes and Correspondence: Decertification at Northwest Tank Service, 1981 (Box-folder 15/23)
    - Subseries E: Marine Power, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 15/24-15/25)
      - Marine Power (1 of 2), 1972-1980 (Box-folder 15/24)
      - Marine Power (2 of 2), 1972-1980 (Box-folder 15/25)
    - Subseries F: Lake Union Dry-dock Company, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 15/26-15/28)
      - Lake Union Dry-dock Company Seniority Lists and Grievances; Correspondence Regarding Matters Brought to the International Union for Resolution, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 15/26)
      - Lake Union Dry-dock Company, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 15/27)
      - Lake Union Dry-dock Company, 1979 (Box-folder 15/28)
    - Subseries G: Rowe Machine Works, Inc., 1979-1980 (Box-folder 15/29)
      - Rowe Machine Works Inc., 1979-1980 (Box-folder 15/29)
    - Subseries H: Northland Marine Lines, Inc., 1968-1976 (Box-folder 15/30)
      - Northland Marine Lines, Inc., 1968-1976 (Box-folder 15/30)
    - Subseries I: Duwamish Shipyard, Inc., 1974-1980 (Box-folder 15/31)
      - Employer File: Duwamish Shipyard, Inc., 1974-1980 (Box-folder 15/31)
    - Subseries J: Lockheed Shipbuilding and Construction Company, 1967-1980 (Box-folder 15/32-15/34)
      - Lockheed Shipbuilding and Construction Company (1 of 2), 1967-1980 (Box-folder 15/32)
      - Lockheed Shipbuilding and Construction Company (2 of 2), 1967-1980 (Box-folder 15/33)
      - Lockheed Shipbuilding and Construction Company, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 15/34)
  - Series IX: Photographs, Ephemera and Posters, 1942-1985 (Box-folder 15/35-15/36; 16/5; 16/7-16/8; 16/12)
    - Photographs and Negatives: Local 541 Officers and Activities, 1977 (Box-folder 15/35)
    - Photographs and Negatives: Local 541 Members and Officers at the Labor Temple in Seattle, WA, 1982 (Box-folder 15/36)
    - Poster: "Send a Shipyard Worker to Congress: Elect Hugh De Lacy", 1942 (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Election Materials: Bob Barnes, Nancy San Carlos, Gene Taylor, Mary Bingham, Red Coan, Joe Warren, 1983 (Box-folder 16/7)
    - Executive Board Election Poster of Oscar Hearde, Bob Barnes, Geraldine Walker, R.L. Willis, Charlie Cross, Linda Crain, and Joe Warren; Large Copy of Settlement Check from Van T. Harrison, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 16/8)
    - Button: 1.5", Orange, "Ship Scalers Union: Member: AFL-CIO: Local 541", 1960-1985 (Box-folder 16/12)
- Ship Scalers, Dry Dock, and Boat Yard Workers Union Records, 1946-1988; 4571-002; 3 boxes 1 oversize folder
  The Ship Scalers, Dry Dock, and Boat Yard Workers Union, Local 541 (Seattle, Washington) Records, Accession 4571-002, ranges in date from 1946 to 1988. The accession consists of the records of the union during that time. Included in the collection are files on the Pablo O'Higgins Mural, Robert A. Barnes' files, legal subject files detailing litigation between members of the union, between the local and international unions, and between Local 541 and various employers, a Constitution of the Laborers International Union of North America, regular meeting, special meeting, committee meeting and executive board meeting minutes, correspondence, strikes, grievances, and elections posters.
  Access restricted: For terms of access contact Special Collections.
  Donor: Bob Barnes, August 08, 2011.
  - Series I: Pablo O'Higgins Mural, 1975-1983 (Box-folder 1/1-1/2)
    - Correspondence: Mexican Muralist Pablo O'Higgins and John Caughlan: Murals Regarding Ship Scalers in Seattle, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Publications about Pablo O'Higgins:Casa de la Cultura, Gobierno del Estado de Nuevo Leon; Museo Diego Rivera; Metamorfosis: Northwest Chicano Magazine of Art and Literature, 1975-1983 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Series II: Robert A. Barnes Files, 1977-1988 (Box-folder 1/3-1/5)
    - Robert A. Barnes Resume: Local 541 Secretary/Treasurer and Assistant Business Representative, 1988 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Robert A. Barnes: Field Notes, 1979 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Robert A. Barnes: Notes and Correspondence: Contract Negotiations and Internal Issues, 1977 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Series III: Legal Subject Files, 1955-1987 (Box-folder 1/6-1/26)
    - Correspondence: Letters and Court Documents: Laborers' International Union of North America, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Washington District Court Case 725-72C2: Local 541 vs. International: Deposition of Van T. Harrison, 1976 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - US District Court: Western Washington: Case No. 725-72C2: Local 541 vs. International: Answers to Interrogatories, 1975 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - US District Court: Western Washington: Case No. 725-72C2: Local 541 vs. International: Index of Pleadings Volume I, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - US District Court: Western Washington: Case No. 725-72C2: Local 541 vs. International: Pleadings; Election Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Legal Documents: Local 541 v. International; Elections, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - US District Court: Seattle: Case No. 725-72C2: Local 541 v. International: Depositions of Joel Wiegert and Forrest Theodore Hilton, 1973 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - US District Court: Western Washington: Case No. 725-72C2: Local 541 vs. International: Depositions and Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - US District Court: Western Washington: Case No. 725-72C2: Local 541 vs. International: Depositions; IRS Appeal by Oscar and Esther Hearde, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Superior Court of Washington: King County: Case No. 87-2-05865-4: Scannell and Bannister v. Barnes, Coan, Rouse, Robinson and Rayland: Judgment, 1987 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Legal Documents and Correspondence: Cases Between Local 541 and the International, 1955-1977 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Correspondence, Court Documents and Press: Elections Issues and Tensions with International, 1948-1982 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Police Report: 541 Office Robbery; Notes and Correspondence: Tensions with International, 1967-1976 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - US District Court: Seattle: Case No. 725-72C2: Local 541 v. International: Answers to Interrogatories, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Transcript of Proceedings: Trial Board of Shipscalers Local 541: Hearing of Charges Brought Against Van T. Harrison, Membership No. 0274299, 1981 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Proof Charges: Lost Income to Local and International, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Local 541: Charges Against Van T. Harrison, 1981 (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Proof of Local 541's Charges Against Van T. Harrison (1 of 3), 1972-1981 (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Proof of Local 541's Charges Against Van T. Harrison (2 of 3), 1972-1981 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Proof of Local 541's Charges Against Van T. Harrison (3 of 3), 1972-1981 (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Statement of Charges Against Van T. Harrison, 1974-1974 (Box-folder 1/26)
  - Series IV: Constitutions, 1971 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - Laborers' International Union of North America: Constitutions, 1971 (Box-folder 1/27)
  - Series V: Meeting Minutes, 1968-1986 (Box-folder 2/1-2/5)
    - Shipscalers Union Local #541: Executive Board Meeting Minutes and Notes (1 of 2), 1968-1980 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Shipscalers Union Local #541: Executive Board Meeting Minutes and Notes (2 of 2), 1968-1980 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Minutes: Scalers Union Special Meetings and Board Meetings; Contract Negotiations, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Minutes: Membership, Executive Board and Benevolent Corporation Meetings (1 of 2), 1980-1986 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Minutes: Membership, Executive Board and Benevolent Corporation Meetings (2 of 2), 1980-1986 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Series VI: Internal Tensions, 1951-1987 (Box-folder 2/6-3/8)
    - Campaign Literature: Local 541 campaign flyers, 1983-1983 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Correspondence: Newsletters, Grievances, Election Protests, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Correspondence: Discrimination, Grievances, Union Leader Indictments, 1951-1987 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Correspondence: Local 541 Suspension; Attempts at Settlement with International, 1977-1986 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Correspondence: Dues Increase; Unauthorized Use of Union Funds, 1972-1985 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Correspondence, Press Clippings, Grievances: Misuse of Union Funds, May Day 1980, Anti-Communist Government Measures, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Legal Transcript: Hearing on Charges Brought Against Van T. Harrison, 1979 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Articles, Flyers, Endorsements for Jesse Jackson, 1973-1986 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Minutes and Notes: Suspension of Local 541, Letters of Community Support, Handwritten Notes, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Membership List; Election Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Pacific: Publication of The Seattle Times: May 2, 1982 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Press and Notes: Anti-Communist Activities, Strike of 1981, Elections, 1951-1981 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Elections and Equal Employment Opportunity Commission Complaint: Oscar Hearde: Discrimination, 1968-1979 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Letters and Statements: Complaints and Investigation of 1974 Election (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Correspondence and Bookkeeping: "New, Fair" Elections Materials, Delinquent Payments, 1956-1975 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Investigation of Unfair 1974 Election; Exhibits and Materials, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Local Elections: Statements and Newsletters, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Membership Lists and Voting Records, 1975 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Membership Lists (1 of 2), 1975 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Membership Lists (2 of 2), 1975 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Correspondence: Northwest EnviroService; Suspension with Laborers' International Union of North America; Meeting Minutes, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Financial Reports, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Publication: Scaler News: January, 1978 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Series VII: Correspondence, 1951-1985 (Box-folder 3/9-3/17)
    - Correspondence: Letters and Reports on Dues Increase Process, 1963-1985 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Correspondence: Lockheed Co. Employee Termination Letters, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Correspondence and Press: Grievances, Strike, Tension with International, 1977-1985 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Correspondence: Dues and Elections, 1975 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - State Legislature Elections: Political Leaflets and Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Personal Correspondence: Unknown Member, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Jurisdiction Issues: Correspondence, Minutes, 1951-1977 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Correspondence and the Laborers' International Union of North America Constitutions, 1969-1981 (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Correspondence: Member Mailings, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - Series VIII: Strikes and Grievances, 1946-1986 (Box-folder 3/18-3/29)
    - Grievances and Related Correspondence, 1961-1978 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Grievances: Todd Pacific Shipyards, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 3/19)
    - Correspondence, Press, and Photographs: Racism and Sexual Harassment at Todd Pacific, Local Issues, Corruption in the International, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 3/20)
    - Bulletins: Corruption at Todd Pacific Shipyards and International Union, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 3/21)
    - Employment Act of 1946; Correspondence Regarding Hiring and Safety Issues, 1946-1972 (Box-folder 3/22)
    - Member Notices: Lockheed Employees. Brief of Union on Arbitration Between Boilermakers Local 104 and Todd Shipyard, 1969-1969 (Box-folder 3/23)
    - Correspondence: Contract Enforcement, 1953-1975 (Box-folder 3/24)
    - Grievances and Bulletins, 1976-1976 (Box-folder 3/25)
    - Lockheed Yard 2 Shop Committee, 1976-1976 (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Shop Committees and Contract Negotiation Strategies, 1976-1976 (Box-folder 3/27)
    - Lockheed Bulletins and Grievances, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 3/28)
    - Health Plan Analysis and Fiberglass Grievance, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3/29)
  - Series IX: Elections Posters, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 4/1-4/2)
    - Elections Posters: Qualified, Experienced, Dedicated: Barnes, San Carlos, Taylor, Bingham, Coan, Warren, 1983 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Elections Poster: Local 79: Gibbons, Benjamin, Anderson, Turnbull, 1982 (Box-folder 4/2)